...let's begin welcome this is a
session on visualizing business data on any device with bing maps my name is
...broader I'm on the bing maps at customer advisory team.
...a little formality here with all sessions
at build and every other microsoft conference we like the gather for your feedback
...very important to us both were improving our sessions in the future and also as a speaker
helped me...become a better speaker...please fill this out at the into the session.
A quick agenda of the things I'll be going through today so I'll do a quick overview of
bing as a platform from there I'll be going into visualizing data on
...maps that writing code.
Then we'll talk about different techniques for visualizing business data on being maps and then finally talk about
cross platform development with the...maps using html five.
So, bing is more than a search engine there's a whole bunch
of developer api is available today...that you can use the start integrating that in
adding smart logic to your own application and in fact microsoft uses
it in nearly every single product today that we have everything from core
...office to windows and even xbox it can use bing in a number of different
ad devices and platforms and then not only do we use it
...at microsoft we have a lot of customers out there that use it has been see listed here just a few
of them but, you can use it as well and there's nothing stopping you getting access to those api swf.
So, that's going on into the visualization...side of things without having...code
just a quick little trivia question here what percentage of business data is often thought
of the have some kind of spatial reference the any ideas.
So, the approximately eighty percent of all business data that the estimate has some kind
of spatial relevance or spatial sense to it, you know, you can imagine all right
you go when you have your customers will every customer has an address for
...they're office or for what.
Where...stores are and
...so that just one of many different types of business data as we there's a lot of potential
...of what you can do with that data when it comes to mapping?
One great tool that's available,
available inexcel twenty thirteen is called our maps allows you to do some really rich
ed deep analytics of data on a map without having...a single...
...can view your data on either a two-d or three-d map
that said the three-d map isn't like what we saw with windows ten maps there it's actually just
a globe with no elevations in at the only elevations you can create would-be three-d
...charts and kind of make sense of any want to analyzer data you don't really need to know
mounds in buildings unless you're doing something about utilities or something inside of a city.
What they can be this in addition to three-d...charge there's heat maps and there
are clustering you can view data as administrative boundary so polygons for
states countries and...even zip code in some areas?
Another really cool features the...the...capability to have storyboards
and timelines and I'll show that the in a little bit in that actually
really makes it for a powerful presentation...need to go through and show data it's a
lot richer than just using a simple powerpoint one other really cool thing with the our maps you can
actually have a custom map so you might have situations where, you know.
The map of the world isn't exactly what you're interested in maybe your
an airport and you have all the data for where people are walking through...the flow data well one
I take a blueprint of your airport make that your custom mapped intern it
journal that data into heat maps you can see where, you know, the congestion is within your airport.
Another really cool things...our maps as part of the big our by stack
...but really cool thing about our be eyes it's not only
a available through excel now it's also available on the web so you can go through
start creating powerful presentations in amp and powerful
reports directly on the web and share them securely without having rate any code as well.
So, let's jump into a demo here.
We'll start off with the...as before...start off the demo...you know,
you guys all have time you don't have to leave right away with the ho everyone's in a
hurry to get to the airport we got a clear traffic alway there.
But,...the jump into a demo here so we're going to start off with a bunch of data that
a found online so this is the nine-one-one incident reports for seattle so,
it's a fairly decent dataset...already has latitude
and longitude which kind of makes things a little bit simpler for me so in if you have our maps
installed...simply go to insert map and launch our maps.
And, hopefully they don't have too many things running the background.
And, there we go...now we get a simple map and if we zoom nbc.
...mouse rather...my finger here we see a whole bunch of blobs points which
don't make a whole lot of sense to us one need thing is
it already automatically identified the latitude longitude columns we don't have to do anything
their however fight had a different call my want to be used as the spatial point of reference I could
set it here but we'll just leave it as that is we want to make
these blob points make a little bit more sense so, you know,
maybe let's take a look at actually...leave it as a what we have...here...add-in
some dave's if...take a look back at what the table actually look like we have this
com called event clearance description so what they different types of a events or
...nine-one-one situation actually was so let's find that...and,
the regal and that's true and other...so now that...data trends
in do still from a somewhat of a blood agar so much of it but we can see it as
a larger and we can actually interact with that so we can start hovering over pieces of
that information and see what it is we can see the different colors for all the different types incidences are different
types of information so this is ok...depending on the...this might make...
sense but the let's do something a little bit more richer there's other situation where you might,
you know, want to create little circles but...this doesn't really work for this data set is just too dense.
Now another option here is a heat maps and others looks pretty pretty cool so
it's a close that we get...this a little bit clear.
And, let's change the...a little bit better.
So, you know, looks very cool but we have one issue here there's
so much density in the center of the seattle we can't really make sense of that either...
can't get too much detail so there's actually a really easy way to handle that so if we go to
the...little settings...
...you have all kinds of different settings for the heap map so we'll change the radius and make it a little bit
smaller...now we can start seeing all the individual locations and let's go
something like that so now we start
seeing some key hot spots in that data and now we know, you know,
really where are the hotspots and...rather than just known that downtown has a lot of nine-one-one calls.
...another really cool thing so I, you know, we go through here and see the
scene so let's do a new
scene and we'll go back to one of the other data tapes they had here.
Or other tables will go back to that table their the blob
...the way review...the data I can quickly click back on to my other
scene and now have that same view same data in even if I go through and,
I move that in a do another new seen a I can.
You come back to this one...view of recur xtwo what it was
before see it it's almost like creating a powerpoint...sense you have all these different
...all the data is interactive so you can imagine if
you're trying to use the your presentation at work and someone says hey
no what's that really big spike in that data and you can say well, actually
...this find out you don't actually have to go through...digging through the data it's just there.
The next...take a look at the...close directions here is if you
...a our by dot com...sign-in and...signing quickly.
We can then the start doing a creating.
They didn't bring my smarter.
...morgan at the scratch that demo.
You can actually go into rbi upload...but it's not limited to excel you
...into other to...sources the
...even connected to a database we have data in a cs v format or another
...can upload it that way you can
...to a file that's on one drive or one of the other a
cloud storage services and it'll automatically pull that in and then you can start building reports which
are very similar to the...pivot charts and pivot tables you would have inside of excel
but all available inside of a web browser and can be shared with your colleagues in a secure
manner so the data in...isn't shared with the world but all of the people you want to share with?
...jump back to the slide deck here.
So, our maps our be...is just some of the ways we're being maps is available
we can start visualizing data without having rate any code there's a lot of other tools
available today so our views also built into a number of different platforms
...excel twenty thirteen it's in sharepoint twenty thirteen and then it's part of our
by it it's actually the same kind of maps that you can get
the in the web version up rbi as well which is the at two-d map where you can
you do that all little circles for the data or you can even create
...polygons for the for the data as well for the if the regions
...crm also has a map integration in it and the different versions of dynamics
...am sharepoint thirteen again there's some additional functionality other than our
view that also allows you to map data of the already any code and then one of the
...one of the first-place of reset...upload data...data on a map that have already coda
sequel porting services back in twenty-eight rtwo
we made that available and it's a very common feature that people use and for
pretty much all these there might be one or two versions of some of the some of these platform
where all the mapping functionality being that it's built into those different pieces up software
those different products there's no licensing required it's just there and made available to you know,
for the our by stuff you definitely need the our
by license but then you get access to our maps and all the other tools that are...our by.
Right moving...take a look at a at visualizing
in business intelligence data on being maps and some very common techniques for doing that
we start off the basics push pins poly lines and polygons
...pre-war the number actually the number
...use of maps today is putting a single push pin on a map and the
yean google go through all the different apps on all your
...devices or on your tablets you'll
find that probably nine-out-of-ten times there's a map with one point on...and that's about it.
That said when it comes to business data it changes drastically people
want to visualize a lot more interesting data and the in the can do that very simply with
pipelines and polygons now when it comes to visualizing that data using these different shapes
there's some cool different techniques you can use to make sense...make better data sets that data
...you know, have a simple icon is nice but you might want to have different types of icons
or customize...are unique to use of situation so if you're showing your customers on a
map you could show the logo all of their company on the map instead of just
... a genera generic push pin on the map that where you can look at the map and instantly know
...that's who that customers I don't even have to click on the push pin to find out the size of an
icon to make sense here so here in the screenshotwe have some circles that are all
scaled based on the size of the data that I've passed...some metric
of that data and then we have no documentation how to do that very easily
in big maps and then of course there's also the color of the icon...the shape of the icon so I
mentioned before you could be logos but if let's say...the some common keep
...you aiff is stuff...used in other things other than maps
...is huge often use like a squares triangles and circles and then also using the
colors green yellow and red of course you can use any color in any
shape the want those are just some common the examples another thing that a lot of people
are aware of is a you can actually chains align style...might if you're drawing a...
liner polygonyou might have a situational let's say you're drawing utility lines on a
map well if all the utility lines are...utility lines that are above ground you might want to
dramas a solid line but if there's some lines that are underground make sense that
...as a...that...you can identify the differences by visually looking at it
and no okay I don't need latter to go work on that line I need to bring a shovel?
When it...with push pins it's great, you know, the visualization but if you start visualizing too many push pins it
gets really cluttered so we take a look on the map there on the last?
And, I think...about what over a thousand push pins on the map you can imagine the more
push pins you put on the less of the map ec and...just doesn't make sense having the
map there because you're not making any sense of the data one way to kind of take care that is
...what's called page...a push...which then takes a
...does a quick analysis of the data on the map in real-time and says okay
these three pins...overlapping or very close to each other this group them together make
...a cluster and let's uniquely identify them and the image on the right all the red circles
are the clusters but if you look closely you'll still see a couple blue circles in there and those are ones
that didn't fall within an existing cluster so as you zoom in these clusters
...breaking apart you start seeing more and more push pins but only for the
or you're looking in so it makes a lot easier to navigate through the data
are also allows you to render a lot more data on the map so instead of hitting performance issues
...javascript once...get up around five thousand push pins you can start
...to hundreds of thousands of push pins on the map and if you start-one
...actually if you take it even a step further and start doing all the algorithms on the server-side or
in the database have I've seen example they've done it with hundreds of millions of push pins?
Density he maps is that...similar to the idea of clustering where you start group
...data and then...uniquely than fighting at based on...the data
...close closely related push pins.
The way the heat maps work here is you start taking every data point give it
a little of gradient circle on as that those circles overlap they start creating darker,
darker areas within map that gradient color or
that transparency that gradient to another color gradient and
...that generates that nicely map like that.
So, clustering heat maps and we have all kinds of
...source code available where you can actually get that functionality into bing
...only two or three lines of code at in the most...
version of course there's tons of customizations you might want to change the color change the
...the intensity and stuff like that and all that's available...of course it's going to the more customize
...make it more lines of code you'll need but...as an example two three lines of code you get to go.
The building is a fairly and it's been around for a while but something I haven't really seen
...to...recently and it's a pretty interesting idea it again it's
similar to clustering...maps...what it does is a breaks the map up into
...evenly spaced or evenly fitted
geometric shape so you might use the over the square triangles
...hexagons like we see in these examples here...you know, all the shapes fit in
all together nicely but, you know,
spatially they're not really all it's not an zip code it's not a city but it's
it evenly size area and then based on that within find out all the data points that
are inside of that ending change the color based on either them some kind of metric or the number of points in there.
...really good example I've seen this there's a
real-estate site in the uk that I've worked with the web and they've
did this for every single property in the uk and they change the color based on the
cell or the last sold the price of that property so now you have rather than trying to show,
you know, like a push pin for each property and...that push pin you have this map of squares that
kind of fits together really nicely and the
or does fitness he hasn't really nicely and you can see this have
...map basically but it's a little bit more in-depth than the gradient
...map of...the density based level we just saw before?
Going a step further another type visualization that...a lot of people like to do
systematic mapping of this type of mappings been around for ages and
...one of the most common ways of visualizing data in sharing data from a
business sense of lot of people when they think of...mapping who
are familiar with that term or this is often confuses...mapping is the web
I think of maybe okay all the country boundaries are all the countries color-coded to based on some kind of, you know,
metric could be like you know, senses data or some other and,
information could be the population ...
very similar to the image we see there in the bottom right.
But, another type of mathematic map it doesn't necessarily have to be a polygon you can start
using poly lines so a great example that is the traffic data inside a bing maps where,
you know, the actual data is the road and we change the color the road based on the flow of
traffic a or could be any kind of metric if we wanted to know the number of
cars for instance or something like that one quick tip if you start doing kind of mapping
like this as you zoom out make sure you focus on larger areas as easy
many can and star breaking into smaller so this screenshot here at the bottom
right with the where actually visualizing the unemployment rates in
the us based on each county in the us...mass of, you know,
dataset and at this zoom level looks...right but you can imagine you can't really
see the smaller polygons or the on the east coast so maybe at this level here might
...made better sense of we were visualizing this as a state
at the state boundaries rather than the county boundaries and if I zoomed in a couple levels then start
showing the county data one benefit of doing that as well as by limiting the view when you're
looking at higher or density data is it reduces the amount of data you actually have to load?
...get better performance so let'sjump in this more demos here.
Okay.
Okay, we're...this will closes up.
Unsavory.
So, we get clients a clustering here so this is a really basic example what's
throw of five thousand push pins on the map.
And, there we go what I've done here is we have a little plus on top of the default push
...indicate that it's a cluster...not click on I
...zoom in so now let's zoom in and we see the cluster
...breaking apart we start seeing some that aren't...see the individual pins
...click on one we see okay this is a single location click on a cluster we see okay this is a
...well that's one that's in
view that's a cluster and there's seventy-seven
a or that's the...but there's five other push pins in that cluster and may
...researching more detail so let's zoom in some more and
...search breaking apart here...get a lot more data so you can imagine if you're
...is the lot easier way to go through navigate that data.
Now let's take a look at the...map once again what we'll do a little bit larger data
...with the twenty five thousand and what update the heat map
...maybe it's...bit bigger here...go fifty thousand?
Ok, so, now we have lots of data on the map the as a he map.
And, we go through...of different settings with that day but this is all based on the number of web points
that are overlapping and it creates
...state gradient we change the radius very similar to the excels demo
edit earlier you can we can change the radius of each single data points so that it uploads
...updates...the map accordingly and
...astray smaller radius all of the best update.
...that again.
...now we have a smaller guy
...he mapper density map ads of resume...here.
Givens you start seeing...a little bit clear and this might make a little bit more sense so this
radius of your data for when you're doing your...mapping would really very depending on the type
...your visualizing so if you're doing keep map based off of, you know, cities your
...radius is that are at least the size of the city but if you're doing
...a heat maps based off of individual incidences like the nine-one-one
incidences we're looking at you only need a small circle for that because that's a small area we can change some
other things like the intensity of...but we won't worry about...also change the colors will
...instead of having no the green yellow and red there...change...something that looks like it's
on a little bit hotter that type thing and there's a number of other options for that as well.
So, next thing or a shows this is a nice little example here with the thematic map that's nice and
interactive and it's all rendered in javascriptas anyone here heard of
...three js.
Yeah, case if you...so for those not familiar with that it's a data-driven
that javascript library for visualizing and rendering nice
uri on maps or non-map on
webpages so it could be charts and a number of other things but it makes it very easy
to visualize data and make it data bounded so a while ago...I say well a couple months ago
made a module for integrating that with being map so that as if...in my zoom
all the data stays within, you know, the right location on the map if we take a quick look at the source code.
So, have a...some styles here but
we skip that here's the whole search go-to it's fairly short
the get the high load up the map?
Actually that's jump individuals due to they...zoomed in there.
...and actually is really simple want version so
...were up the map here initially and then after redo that we load in the register and
...the three module.
For being maps and then once you go to do that
...then create eighty-three layer for...map and then we specify
were data is so I'm using a data type called topple json...a fairly new data
type if you're if you work...spatial data files before there's a...one called
...json which is ...way of...storing the geis
...spatial data as json and,
the top of jason's basically compressed version of that...makes it a little bit our
matrix significantly smaller...megabyte file turns into about two hundred kilobyte file so I'm
using that just for performance reason for the loading but then I'm able to pull that data in
an water that data pulled in...basically just using sb...to them
...that data on the map and...and, the map itself or
the module itself actually take care of the updating of the data on the map so that it's always position in the
crack place if we take a look at the ad the literacy one much of
...showing it's a little bit more advance because they've...now I'm pulling in at to
file some pulling in both the topple json file for the county data
...for the via that the states but I'm also pulling in tab
spaced deb data file that has all the literacy data so I'm the
merging that data together and then rendering on the map so.
I also have a little bit of code here for
...sky...legend there but if we dis focus on the code that was used to
render that map we're looking at maybe twenty,
twenty five lines of code that total which,
you know, if you try to create the heap map like that but in the...have taken quite a long-time and,
it works very well you...screenshot I showed earlier with the at county datacan't
visualizing...hit on a map is very hard...with javascript because there's so much data?
All right so,
I mentioned a lot of these the modules like the clustering he map
...three modules there's a lot of module built into being mapped there's also a
locked let's zoom in here available online so we have a pretty big
...developer community around being maps and then over the years
you been developing modules are basically take...something really...want to make
...reusable so we turn it into a...so they can be added in very easily so there's
I've created a number of model but there's a lot of other models...have been created by some of
...being maps and vp so things from like drawing tools clustering
heat maps and being able to actually another interesting
one bottom is well-known text if you work with any the spatial data
and sequel server well-known text is a way
to represent spatial data as a string so there's a module that allows you to easily take that string
...on being maps take...data on bing maps and a and turn it into a string that
...you can easily take that data from sequel server
and connected up to bing maps and having your own custom application.
All right let's the jump back to the slide deck.
Right trivia question number two and how big would
a single jpeg of the role be at zoom level nineteen so at zoom of nineteen
...got thirty centimeter resolutionimagery the anyone get a guests?
Now it's a really big.
The image would be, you know, hundreds of millions pixels
...pixels and...are actually...a lot more than that but it that it's a massive image
just a road map would be an image of just the road data would be while over
...hundred terabites and the era aerial imagery be overhang...
to half a petabyte if not more and that's just the flat two-d maps you can imagine the maps
we have now and windows tim the three-d data how much bigger that data is gets.
But, we're using bing maps today in javascript
...have been for a long-time so how do we actually get that much data visualized on a map.
And, that brings us to tyler is which is another really common way...visualizing data on maps and,
allows you to visualized large data sets as well.
The basic idea is we take this giant image me cut it up into a bunch of
evenly even size squares ...which are two-hundred-and-fifty six pixels by
...six pixels inferring maps and most other major mapping providers?
And, then we give them all unique...naming conventionswe use what's called
...quad key naming convention so the idea here if you take a look at level
...the top left images, you know,
we give it zero then the next one's one-two-three
resume into the next level...let's say resume into the you know,
the area of tile to we keep that number twoid and
...we start doing zero one-two-three a again and keep appending that
autonomy end up creating this unique string that points to that exact tile.
Another common method is using what's called xyz soul
...we might say okay it's three tiles to the right at for tiles to
our down and then zoom level ten and that would basically it just
...you storing three variables instead of one but at the day it takes to the
exact same data and I can all be dumping maps another method that's
use sometimes is bounding boxes where people say okay I have my tile is within
this...square of coordinates and then load that up
...added again can also be the visualize...being that's very easily.
Now there's a couple different types of tile layers
...their static taylor's and dynamic taylor's to static ones basically
that's a I have an image of...the blueprint for a mall and
I want to visualize that on top of bing maps and make it so I can zoom in zoom out and
panned so what static and tiles butsince...data is really changing sacked
as a greater approach for that and basically...there's a lot of ways to go about this but
one great tools called microsoft mapcruncher...allows...load up either...image or
...file and cross-referenced
a minimum of three data points on your image to physical points on the maps of, you know,
you the four corners of the building is usually pretty good...way to go and then it you press a single
... create your or mash up your tiles
and it actually goes through and generates all these images free which...match are naming conventions for maps
...then just upload these up to your web server and axes
...just like any other image...in this case...it to be...just
...url to where stored and the map control go through and request them as needed so
extremely simple to do you don't need to know rate a whole lot of code...actually the
...in a tile layer again is about two lines of code one to create the tyler and one to
added to the map but one of the downsides this approach is very hard to maintain you can imagine ok
...blueprints changed and I go through do this cross referencing again and,
re upload in...the data.
So, you the pros and cons to that approach
you trading simplicity for a little bit harder management another the other type
your dynamic tellers is the ideal for when you have constantly changing data are really big
datasets...you know, storage limitations on...you know, and, server look at a
...at the whole worldwe just saw a single image of
...maps is five hundred terabytes if you do the whole world but you can imagine trying to store all
that data on...just isn't that manageable we can do is you
can actually cut that image on-the-fly using a web service or you can even take
...data from say sequel server and render it on-the-fly as a tile and rent an overlay
that on top the map so it's a little bit more complicated in terms the architecture but we actually have all the
source code available if you...one of our demos for it you can actually change it
two-point-one your datasets and if you have the right call name for the spatial data
in your database the or update decode...point to the same name you'll be able to get on the
map in about ten minutes or less and start visualizing large data
sets I gave a presentation two-week herb two months ago on visualizing big data one my
partner's uses...exact same technique...visualizing a half a million
complex polygons on the map and that the dataset was about sixty four gigabytes
...six-four gigabytes raw data on the map and being able to interact with it as well
so, you know, taylor's even though it's an image on the map being that your data stored in
the spatial database you can actually find out what people of clicked on bison
...a quick request against the database so it's very useful for, you know,
constantly changing large data sets so here's an idea of
...a typical architecture for that might look like the
...your data your vector data somewhere or your spatial data some marceleo sequel
...a great place for that another great place if you're using bing maps is
...map spatial data services...the spatial data services essentially of
wrapper around a single table inside of
sql larger and exposes that table as a
spatial rest service so you can imagine okay...uploaded on
or maybe a cs v file or something like that to a database table.
And, now you have to go through and...all that kind of code to expose it to do a...
I want to radius certain stuff like that the spatial data services takes away all that complexity
you basically upload your file and now you have a restaurants in the rest services can allow you to do
...searches,
searches along a route within a polygon you can do even
...complex we went out and...for complex data types you can start, you know, doing intersection
...not now I've got all my boundaries from my sales
...show me all the boundaries that the user just...all the ones that intersect with that.
From there,...we have an all simple service inside of asher that we can then
...take that data and rendered as a tile and we have all that code available is a lot of partners
...solutions for that as well and the one nice thing to use also the cache
the data if it's not changing that frequently it is changing frequently...you can still get away
with...one-minute or five-minute cash and that can make a huge difference...of users so
...using something like the blobs verge is a great simple way to do that I
get the example be doing here's just using the local stored but we do have code sample that
you in blob storage and then finally take all that data we overlay that service over top the map
is a tile they're using that to lines of code I mentioned and we get a map that
looks something like that?
So, let's take a look at that.
So, ...can map so here's the project
that we put together this code samples part of white papers we have a way people who just put together that
goes step-by-step how to do this and a lot more and if we show how-to-do-it both
the sequel server and also the being spatial data services and using local cash and
measure cash and things like that so if we take a quick look at the
...the sequel server approach.
Or...we have to do is.
That's why we want to have the cash...it goes through and.
...zoom in a little bit here.
So, we go through here and we disclose down here we go through which,
you know, do a little bit math years we...use the...map style system?
The figure out what.
What how they actually requested may and figure out what data is
in that in that tiles we basically calculate the bounding box of that tile and say give me all the data
...that rebounding box and then we have a little tool here that allows us to
...all this data or a sql geometry or sequel spatial
type on image using a system that drawing scifi...school down here...take a quick
look at a polygon and we basically go through in the
we basically take create an array ofpoint...objects and pass it to the
...to a graphics path insistent drawing and rendered on top of an image so seeing that
inaction?
...the jump back over here so I've already loaded
it up so recently I was in the market for buying a new house I just moved
from the uk to the us and the one of the things I was interested
in doing was finding out okay were the property boundaries of these houses I'm looking at and
...this property boundary data is often called the
...off...known as partial data and there's a couple real-estate sites that
do show you that data but I found that the often limit the zoom level you can go to so
...I can see the property boundary of just that house but I can't really see the neighborhood that
well so this example here.
We're now strong all that data up in the spatial data services a big maps and then taken
that down rendering as a tile overlaying it on the map so I'll change the style your
...libby clear with the aerial imagery so now we have all these different polygons I can zoom around
...searching the neighborhood...all the property boundaries for everyone
in the area so this data said I have here's for king county
in washington it's about four hundred megabytes and size and
able to navigate or around it very easily...start zooming
on start seeing quite large areas of all the properties of course the further
you zoom out the harder it gets the see in some areas because these such a small areas or
small properties in some areas and as resume and we can start seeing more and more data.
They're going to go back to the...slide deck.
And, move on to our next topic.
Which is the using being maps and cross platform maps using html five
so when it comes using maps across platform a apps there's a lot of different
approaches the...a native dot net code in it's great for
good performance and if you need offline maps but, we're kind of limited at the moment
...platforms that's available to use we have offline maps available in windows store apps
in windows phone so, you know, you can do this for windows phone eight-point...have offline maps
...any windows ten apps of for phone in both the and pc?
What hybrid apps the using javascript html?
Is a nice appropriate
...target all the different mobile browsers out there you can target all the pc
browsers and pretty much any other device that can render a web page?
One down possible downside is if you're on a and oslo wireless connection it could be a little bit slow loading the data
because you can't store locally or you can't, you know, download the...the maps offline so you
gotta make all these request for the map images so that,... there's a tradeoff their for simplicity
for per performance but if you're just doing a single push pin on a map
it's pretty straightforward pretty easy to do.
One thing that a lot of people overlook is another approach is
actually use web services you may have a situation where you don't actually need an interactive
...you just need an image of a map or maybe want to do some kind of
...calculation so great examples core tom have you ever you set up
...set up a meeting you put in the location...for all
the office location that you can have it or the building and have your meeting and then, you know,
an hour before half-hour...tells you all need to start
...meeting now because a lot...current traffic conditions you get
...just make it and it shows you a little map with the road on it will all that's using being maps
...the back-end...you know, the image of the map of courses coming from
a or imagery service and it's just a static image but the calculation
of the travel time is just using a routing service so using something as simple as,
you know, calculate calculating direction from point a to point b
three do a simple calculation ahead of time and say okay well if...the at the meeting is, you know,
an hour away and
...usually so let's, you know, an hour and a half before duke routing calculation and see what
kind of time it is with current traffic conditions and then that tell the user ok at
...time to go now or hey you...another ten minutes...then you get start going and that's what
...is doing in the back and it's basically just using our existing services for doing that?
So, one thing...as I said before...to focus on that mainly html five
staff however if I highly recommend take a look at session seven-five seven which was the
ad the universal windows apps or maps in apps the session that was
a presented on wednesday and that's a great weighty
...get an introduction to the new maps and windows ten
and all the three-d capabilities that are in there and the offline maps as well.
hybrid apps...using html five javascript we heard a lot about that at the conference
this week and it has been around for quite a while and the general idea is you...once and use
it everywhere so there's a lot of different development...you can take to get
to that you know, to do this by...the hard-core core
will method would be do they create a mobile website and algal through and create an individual
apps for each platform that then ...the web browser control or the web
...control depending on the platform and just loads your web page or your map
up inside there that's a good approach if you already have an existing app that's already written for
an individual platform but if you're starting from scratch...you might be want to use, you know,
something like apache cordova which we seen a lot today especially with all the new functionality inside of
...studio twenty fifteen and it being built in there
and it makes it a lot easier but another approaches well if
you're creating examine based app you can easily use what's called the hybrid a web
view control which is available...get into the exact same thing that we seen here but with the other
two approaches to take your html five map in
...it very easily into your examine app that said for examine
the another interesting thing is a...a saddam one of the other...for maps and someone
...a little experiment and they actually created a wrapper on one of our native controls to actually work examined
as well so...a little bit more information on...will be sure to share that are blog couple tips when you do
used html five the javascript controls for a for being maps
...retiring cross platform it is that enable
high dpi of...inside the maps there's a one-line...say use
...high dpi maps that way...like a mobile screen which has hide
...ansi get the higher-quality maps that data that have bigger labels
are easier to read otherwise you end up with a small labels and you can't really assume that well the cool thing
about enabling that
is map control smart enough to know if it's not on a high pixel density screen and
...will go back to the standard maps so that way there if you are using
...desktop that or that doesn't have a high-density screen you...have end up
these massive labels on the map e it's all come back and is a relative experience?
Another useful tips so if you try to access an external...javascript file for
...that posted on the web the in a windows that, you know, when to store app or windows
...app you'll likely end up with some headaches with the security issues
...reason for that is the deal it's just part of the architecture windows a
...logic call-in external files very easily there's some work-arounds for that
...there's a very are very easy way to get around that would bing maps we have
an sdk for windows eight that works in javascript it's about ninety nine-point nine percent
identical to our web control there's only one difference in there and it's so minor
that I'm not even bother going into the to the explaining up so, if you actually install that into
yourapache could of app you can then simply just?
Update descriptive reference for when you goaded
...the employer windows store up and it'll use that local copy of
being maps now another great benefit of doing that is bringing that it's local
...end up in the byte code caching which means it's going to load a large fast because they...have to
...to web grab that map control.
So, simple, you know, architecture of how...apache could overlaps...with
...your...you know, you with your html javascript
somebody's port pushing bing maps and then in a loaded on the map.
Zimmer app a little bit different they these approaches mentioned earlier would use the hybrid a web
you control and then pass that into a csharp app inside examine?
So, you had the session I was talking about with the native wrapper around
...for examine was session sixty-seven so you might want to check that out as well
...contact the speaker deceiving get a copy of their code so let's take a look at the
...samples here and demos.
so, first they wanted to start off with is the...interactive sdk if
you're developing an app web using being maps and javascript this is a great place...start
so, if we go in here let's say we want to loaded...it gives us the code we need to load that
...that map...want to make a couple change...say we want to push pin
...at the default push pin and we see how easy it is to
...into the map so.
Let's go through in create a basic cordova app.
And, that's here.
And, whoa that's see that's your that's a good name.
So, as that loads up we're going to do here is that
find one that actually this push pin one looks good to express the view html
...it gives us all the html that makes up that
...that map view and we'll just copy and paste this over.
The to our app so let's close that
...just open up the index file.
Ariel...set the zero.
All right so now we've added...map that's very simple and, you know,
we get...is load up a map control and then add a pushed into it and actually
it's move get rid of this function years we don't have the press a button...now...that button.
And, then if we deploy that app...see
being maps inside the android emulator or.
...am using the emulator that's inside of it google chrome
several yet deploy to their to start seeing the map loaded up very easily.
...stigma bit longer so as that loads
and I'll talk about another echoed sample I have so while ago as the
...several years ago we had people want to
cost platform developing maps and the reason html five so I download the code samples we
...and on msdn and just for fun I tossed them into and apache could
...so we'll come back to the second...could overlap
and it just worked so this is the.
This one here is the demos this was an app that was created several years ago
didn't make any code changes simply just drop the code into and apache cordova app
...visual studios and now we have this map here that we can
zoom in has a bunch of different buns so we can...that's...some traffic on top of the map.
And, of course of the work...doing.
But, any case there's one there's all that and it's just...do any changes to its if...done
...now going back to the other demo that we're starting put together all right we got...
map the put canonical we see a couple issues here first one is we got this little message
crossed map saying that, you know, you have some issues with credential this...the other thing another issue we have is
you know, the map is pretty small we want to fill the whole screen and maybe that navigation
but we don't really need the zoom...only the panned on we just want to see the
...the at the drop down for changing the map view.
So, let's go back to our code sample here.
...so now we're back well that's the old one.
Let's close that.
That's a good of my back up here.
I jordan real to...the matter.
So, this one here now this is
basically the almost the same app I made a few key changes.
First changes...the very top.
And, what I've done is I've added the view port information that way there
that when I my am web apple take up the full-screen?
The next thing I've done is in of added my credentials to get rid of that error message across the screen and
...settings the first one is a enabled high dpi...set that...true that way there I get the
higher-resolution...the tiles when I'm using a high pixel
density screen of change the, you know, the navigation...the scale barley
we don't need the scale bar on the map because it takes up some room don't need the at the dashboard we only want
the little drop down and...a couple other different settings that I've changed as well.
We still end up just adding a simple put
...map one others the difference between this code on the other code is they got rid of all the style settings
to be automatic the full thing I...to a certain pixel size now we run that.
Actually get the latest version visual students little bit faster...this part.
What's up.
So, ...as loads up here a couple key things that...a couple cool things...checkout if you have
...check...the bing booth on this third-floor...rate kill that
in reload on the third-floor we've been there for the last couple of days
...a lot of people come by we want hear from you get your feedback
...cool thing to check out in if you go to bing listens
...user voice dot com you can that provide feedback on all of are different being products
...you know, bing maps or any of the other be maps api and we want
...what your ideas are what your features are what you'd love to have all right now why is this loading.
Now let's try this again.
...so now we got our map it takes up
the full-screen no more error message...
actually got rid of the drop down as well but we're going to go through we can pan zoom the map and
...looks very nice because I'm doing this on my laptop and art on actual device the it's not using the
hide that pixel density at...tiles because it doesn't need it for this screen but if I was
using mobile devices would change the tile sets to the labels are a little bit bigger.
The very simple.
To get started, you know, anyone can do this like.
The initial example I showed you had...for...
javascript one real main the...line of html.
But, you can do this yourself and get started
...today right so let's the back to the powerpoint here.
And, we...trivia question number three.
What-you online the microsoft tool to...to visualize your data on a map without having
...code and the ideas.
Re sp and attention to...
All right the microsoft our rbi public previous if you go to the...dot
...give that a tried either today or network next week and the easily
uploading visualize your data on top of a map.
So, now we get to the call of actions from the session here the first one of course
...rbi in try visualized media map...you but I often get
...situation...customers want to see their data on a map, you know, they don't need it to be a custom app
...one and see what it looks like...a great way to do that.
...use being maps in your apps a lot of different api...a lot of different tools so we can
...with that check out session seven-five seven as I said the learn more about the maps
and windows ten and you know, false on twitter area at bing
maps I what monitor that along with a number of the people on our team...you got any kind of feedback
...if you just love us...a tweet in a...love to hear from and also check out
...blogs that...dot com slash maps...go get to get stay
...on what's what's do with being maps...the make...announcements there.
Will be...to three blog posts a week and we also do a lot of technical blogs on
there as well so, you know, if you want to figure out how to do all this cross platform stuff with the
...over we have a couple blog post...there the same thing with the dynamic
tile...and actually everything I've shown here we have blog posts for but,
you can also use the comments...to get reach out to us we don't use the twitter you can also
use that reaches on the forums of use msdn for armor stack
overflow either go to the bing maps forms and msdn or tag your stack overflow
...that with bing maps are being dash maps and then we'll be sure to see it in
...help you out whether...a simple question or if you need
...the information about being maps or you know,
you...possibly want us to come and talk to your company more about what...maps can do?
...stop but that...thank you for attending the session please
deal go through your evaluations...the...
The thank you very much.